Guide to the Pulp Science Fiction and Detective Fiction Periodical Collection 1940-1983 MSS 145 MSS.145
Fales Library and Special Collections
Pulp Science Fiction and Detective Fiction Periodical Collection
1940-1983
Fales Library and Special Collections
Fales Library
MSS.145
13.5 Linear Feet in 9 boxes
The Pulp Science Fiction and Detective Fiction Periodical Collection comprises pulp science fiction and mystery serials from the 1940s to the 1980s with a concentration in the 1940s.
Provenance
The materials were gathered from various sources over a period of time from 1957-1990.
Access Restrictions
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Fales Library and Special Collections, fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
Historical Note
At the beginning of the twentieth century, the genres of science fiction and detective fiction were still in their nascent forms, dominated by the influences of Jules Verne and H.G. Wells and Edgar Allen Poe and Arthur Conan Doyle, respectively. By the 1950s, many of the genre conventions now associated with both genres had been formulated and refined in the medium of pulp magazines. Monthly and bi-monthly publications like Amazing Stories, Astounding Science Fiction, Ellery Queen's Mystery Magazine, and Famous Fantastic Mysteries (all held in the collection) as well as Weird Tales, Wonder Stories, and Black Mask (later acquired by Ellery Queen's Mystery Magazine) offered venues with a wide variety of topical focuses and styles in which writers could experiment and develop their craft.
With their often lurid covers and sensational subject matter, the pulps offered low-priced fantastic entertainment to their largely working class readers. However, the authors also engage directly with issues of immediate significance to their readers, including the dark side of technological development, war, population growth, and immigration. Pulp magazines offer a significant cross-section of the fantasies and concerns of working class readers of the period.
Scope and Content Note
The Fales Library's collection of pulp science fiction and mystery magazines spans five decades (1940s-1980s), and includes work by prominent figures in the history of both genres. The issues in the collection offer researchers the opportunity both to chart the development of genre conventions on a large-scale basis and to track the literary development of major authors such as Isaac Asimov, Robert A. Heinlein, John Dickson Carr, and Robert Bloch.
The collection holds large runs of Amazing Stories, Astounding Science Fiction, Ellery Queen's Mystery Magazine, and Famous Fantastic Mysteries in addition to odd issues of The Magazine of Fantasy and Science Fiction and single issues of Galaxy and Fantastic Adventures.
The materials collected in each magazine vary from serialized reprintings of previously published novels in Famous Fantastic Mysteries to the original stories and science writing found in Astounding Science Fiction. Each magazine offers a different version of its genre. In the science fiction magazines researchers will find a clear contrast between John W. Campell's insistence that stories published in Astounding be based on plausible science and the more fantastic premises shared by contributions to Amazing Stories. Ellery Queen's Mystery Magazine offers an interesting view of the development of mystery novel conventions in that it began with an emphasis on the logical, contemplative detectives of Agatha Christie, Ellery Queen, and Dorothy Sayers but later expanded into the field of the hardboiled mystery with the acquisition of Black Mask in May 1953. Ellery Queen's Mystery Magazine was also concerned with locating precursors of detective fiction in little known tales by figures like Abraham Lincoln and Walt Whitman. Famous Fantastic Mysteries stretched genre definitions bringing together authors as diverse as H. G. Wells, H. Rider Haggard, G. K. Chesterton, and Jack London between its covers.
The forties materials in the collection are especially interesting as a cross section of popular culture during World War Two. Many Astounding authors had served in the military and the magazine's science features focus on keeping up with military technologies during the war years. Furthermore, many of these journals would have been read by members of the armed forces (issues of Ellery Queen's Mystery Magazine in the collection from May 1944 to April 1946 are marked "Overseas edition for the Armed Forces").
SERIES I: Amazing Stories
Created by editor Hugo Gernsback in 1926, Amazing Stories was the first pulp completely dedicated to publishing science fiction. The collection holds an incomplete run of issues from the forties (June 1940 to January 1947) during the tenures of editors B.G. Davis (1940-1946) and Raymond A. Palmer (1946-1949). For the period represented in the collection, Amazing Stories was published on a monthly basis with the exception of the period from September 1943 until May 1946, in which it was a bimonthly. Notable authors represented in the collection include Robert Bloch, E. E. Smith and Edgar Rice Burroughs.
SERIES II: Astounding Science Fiction
Under the editorial direction of John W. Campbell (1938-1971) Astounding Science Fiction (later renamed Analog Science Fiction) was especially known for its commitment to scientifically accurate science fiction, manifested both in the fiction and the popular science writing collected in each issue. Astounding published the first works of Robert Heinlein, L. Ron Hubbard and Lester del Rey and important work by Isaac Asimov, Ted Sturgeon and many others. The collection features an incomplete run of issues from October 1940 until February 1955.
SERIES III: Ellery Queen's Mystery Magazine
Ellery Queen's Mystery Magazine was launched in the fall of 1941 by Lawrence E. Spivak of The Mercury Press. It was heralded as the brainchild of Ellery Queen himself, really the two-cousin writing team of Frederic Dannay and Manfred B. Lee. Dannay served as editor-in-chief, under the name of Ellery Queen, from 1941 until his death in 1982. Throughout its history the magazine has featured a mixture of original work and reprints of authors such as Rudyard Kipling, William Faulkner, Ernest Hemingway, Norman Mailer, and Alice Walker. The collection features an incomplete run of issues from May 1943 to March 1961. In this period the magazine was published on a bimonthly basis from May 1943 to March 1945 and on a monthly basis subsequently. Issues from May 1944 to April 1946 are marked "Overseas edition for the Armed Forces."
SERIES IV: Famous Fantastic Mysteries
Famous Fantastic Mysteries was founded to reprint fantasy and SF material from the old Frank A. Munsey magazines (Argosy, All-Story, etc.). Some novels were serialized in the early issues, until the companion Fantastic Novels was started and began publishing complete novels. After FFM was bought by Popular Pubs in 1943, the fiction policy changed to the reprinting of novels that had previously appeared only in book form, such as works by H.G. Wells and H. Rider Haggard. The collection holds an incomplete run of issues from March 1940 to February 1949.
SERIES V: Miscellaneous Magazines
Collects four issues of The Magazine of Fantasy and Science Fiction from the seventies and eighties and single issues of Galaxy and Fantastic Adventures.
Arrangement
Series are organized alphabetically by publication and chronologically within each series.
Missing Title
Series I: Amazing Stories
Series II: Astounding Science Fiction
Series III: Ellery Queen's Mystery Magazine
Series IV: Famous Fantastic Mysteries
Series V: Miscellaneous Magazines
Related Material at Fales Library and Special Collections
Levy Dime Novel Collection (MSS.028)
Gay and Lesbian Pulp Fiction Collection (MSS.116)
New American Library Archive (MSS.070)
Separated Material
There is no information about materials that are associated by provenance to the described materials that have been physically separated or removed.
Detective and mystery stories, American |v Periodicals.; Science fiction, American |v Periodicals.; Periodicals; Clarke, Arthur C. (Arthur Charles ), 1917-2008; Chesterton, G. K. (Gilbert Keith ), 1874-1936; Carr, John Dickson, 1906-1977; Campbell, John Wood, 1910-1971; Burroughs, Edgar Rice, 1875-1950; Bradbury, Ray, 1920-; Bloch, Robert, 1917-1994; Asimov, Isaac, 1920-1992; Wells, H. G. (Herbert George), 1866-1946; Whitman, Walt, 1819-1892; Smith, E. E. (Edward Elmer), 1890-1965; Sturgeon, Theodore; Pal, George; Queen, Ellery; Lincoln, Abraham, 1809-1865; London, Jack, 1876-1916; Herbert, Frank; Hubbard, L. Ron (La Fayette Ron), 1911-1986; Hammett, Dashiell, 1894-1961; Heinlein, Robert A. (Robert Anson), 1907-1988; Dick, Philip K.; Haggard, H. Rider (Henry Rider), 1856-1925
- Series I: Amazing Stories
  Scope and Contents note
  An incomplete run from June 1940 to January 1947. Also included is one issue of Amazing Stories Quarterly from Spring 1942 which reprints the August, September and October 1941 monthly issues.
  - Amazing Stories v.14 #6, June 1940 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Amazing Stories v.15 #2, February 1941 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Amazing Stories v.16 #1, January 1942 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    General note
    Alfred Bester, "Life for Sale"
  - Amazing Stories v.16 #6, June 1942 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Amazing Stories v.16 #7, July 1942 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Amazing Stories v.16 #10, October 1942 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Amazing Stories v.16 #11, November 1942 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Robert Bloch, "Murder from the Moon"
  - Amazing Stories v.17 #1, January 1943 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Amazing Stories v.17 #2, February 1943 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Robert Bloch (as Tarleton Fiske), "Phantom from the Film"; Edgar Rice Burroughs, "Skeleton Men of Jupiter"
  - Amazing Stories v.17 #3, March 1943 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Amazing Stories v.17 #4, April 1943 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Robert Bloch "Never Trust a Demon"
  - Amazing Stories v.17 #5, May 1943 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Amazing Stories v.17 #6, June 1943 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Amazing Stories v.17 #7, July 1943 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Amazing Stories v.17 #8, August 1943 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Amazing Stories v.17 #9, September 1943 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Amazing Stories v.17 #10, November 1943 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Amazing Stories v.20 #5, August 1946 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Amazing Stories v.20 #6, September 1946 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Amazing Stories v.20 #7, October 1946 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Amazing Stories v.20 #8, November 1946 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Amazing Stories v.21 #1, January 1947 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Amazing Stories Quarterly v.2 #2, Spring 1942 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    Edgar Rice Burroughs "Yellow Men of Mars"; "Invisible Men of Mars"
- Series II: Astounding Science Fiction
  An incomplete run of issues from October 1940 until February 1955.
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.27 #1, September 1940 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.27 #2, October 1940 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.27 #3, November 1940 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.27 #5, January 1941 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    Robert Heinlein (as Anson MacDonald) "The Sixth Column" First of three part serial, continued in 27.6 and 27.7
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.27 #6, February 1941 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.27 #7, March 1941 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.27 #8, April 1941 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    Isaac Asimov "Reason;" Ted Sturgeon "The Microcosmic God"
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.27 #9, May 1941 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.27 #10, June 1941 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.27 #11, July 1941 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    Robert Heinlein, "Methuselah's Children" First of three part serial, continued in 27.12 and 28.1; Alfred Bester, "The Probable Man"
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.27 #12, August 1941 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.28 #1, September 1941 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    Isaac Asimov, "Nightfall"; Alfred Bester "Adam and No Eve"
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.28 #2, October 1940 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.28 #3, November 1941 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    E. E. Smith "Second Stage Lensman" First of four part serial continued in 28.4, 28.5, 28.6
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.28 #4, December 1941 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.31 #3, May 1943 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.31 #4, June 1943 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.31 #5, July 1943 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.31 #6, August 1943 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.32 #1, September 1943 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    Ray Bradbury, "Doodad"
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.32 #2, October 1943 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.32 #4, November 1943 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.32 #5, January 1944 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.32 #6, February 1944 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.33 #1, March 1944 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.33 #2, April 1944 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.33 #3, May 1944 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.33 #4, June 1944 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.33 #6, August 1944 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    Isaac Asimov, "The Big and the Little"
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.34 #1, September 1944 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.34 #2, October 1944 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    Isaac Asimov "The Wedge"
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.34 #3, November 1944 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    Theodore Sturgeon, "Killdozer"
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.34 #4, December 1944 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.34 #5, January 1945 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.34 #6, February 1945 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.35 #1, March 1945 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    Isaac Asimov, "Blind Alley"
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.35 #2, April 1945 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.35 #3, May 1945 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.35 #4, June 1945 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.35 #5, July 1945 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.35 #6, August 1945 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.36 #1, September 1945 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.36 #5, January 1946 (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.37 #3, May 1946 (Box 4, Folder 67)
    Arthur C. Clarke, "Rescue Party"
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.37 #4, June 1946 (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.37 #5, July 1946 (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.37 #6, August 1946 (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.38 #1, September 1946 (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.38 #2, October 1946 (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.38 #3, November 1946 (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.38 #4, December 1946 (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.39 #1, March 1947 (Box 4, Folder 75)
    Isaac Asimov, "Little Lost Robot"
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.39 #2, April 1947 (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.39 #3, May 1947 (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.39 #4, June 1947 (Box 4, Folder 78)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.39 #5, July 1947 (Box 4, Folder 79)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.39 #6, August 1947 (Box 4, Folder 80)
    L. Ron Hubbard "The End is Not Yet" First of three part serial, continued in 40.1, 40.2
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.40 #1, September 1947 (Box 4, Folder 81)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.40 #2, October 1947 (Box 4, Folder 82)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.40 #3, November 1947 (Box 4, Folder 83)
    E. E. Smith, "Children of the Lens" First of four part serial continued in 40.4, 40.5, 40.6, 41.1
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.40 #4, December 1947 (Box 4, Folder 84)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.40 #5, January 1948 (Box 4, Folder 85)
    Isaac Asimov, "Now You See It"
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.40 #6, Febraury 1948 (Box 4, Folder 86)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.41 #1, March 1948 (Box 4, Folder 87)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.41 #2, April 1948 (Box 4, Folder 88)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.41 #3, May 1948 (Box 4, Folder 89)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.41 #4, June 1948 (Box 4, Folder 90)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.41 #5, July 1948 (Box 4, Folder 91)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.41 #6, August 1948 (Box 4, Folder 92)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.42 #1, September 1948 (Box 4, Folder 93)
    Arthur C. Clarke, "Inheritance"
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.42 #3, November 1948 (Box 4, Folder 94)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.42 #4, December 1948 (Box 4, Folder 95)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.42 #5, January 1949 (Box 5, Folder 96)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.42 #6, February 1949 (Box 5, Folder 97)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.43 #1, March 1949 (Box 5, Folder 98)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.43 #2, April 1949 (Box 5, Folder 99)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.43 #3, May 1949 (Box 5, Folder 100)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.43 #4, June 1949 (Box 5, Folder 101)
    Theodore Sturgeon "Minority Report"
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.43 #5, July 1949 (Box 5, Folder 102)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.43 #6, August 1949 (Box 5, Folder 103)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.44 #1, September 1949 (Box 5, Folder 104)
    Arthur C. Clarke, "Hide and Seek"
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.44 #2, October 1949 (Box 5, Folder 105)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.44 #3, November 1949 (Box 5, Folder 106)
    Isaac Asimov, "…And Now You Don't", three part serial continued in 44.4, 44.5; Robert Heinlein, "Gulf", two part serial continued in 44.4
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.44 #4, December 1949 (Box 5, Folder 107)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.44 #5, January 1950 (Box 5, Folder 108)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.44 #6, February 1950 (Box 5, Folder 109)
    L. Ron Hubbard, "To the Stars"; two part serial continued in 45.1
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.45 #1, March 1950 (Box 5, Folder 110)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.45 #2, April 1950 (Box 5, Folder 111)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.45 #3, May 1950 (Box 5, Folder 112)
    L. Ron Hubbard, "Dianetics: The Evolution of a Science"
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.45 #4, June 1950 (Box 5, Folder 113)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.45 #5, July 1950 (Box 5, Folder 114)
    Robert A. Heinlein, "Shooting 'Destination Moon'"
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.45 #6, August 1950 (Box 5, Folder 115)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.46 #1, September 1950 (Box 5, Folder 116)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.46 #2, October 1950 (Box 5, Folder 117)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.46 #3, November 1950 (Box 5, Folder 118)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.46 #4, December 1950 (Box 5, Folder 119)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.46 #5, January 1951 (Box 5, Folder 120)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.46 #6, February 1951 (Box 5, Folder 121)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.47 #1, March 1951 (Box 5, Folder 122)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.47 #2, April 1951 (Box 5, Folder 123)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.47 #3, May 1951 (Box 5, Folder 124)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.47 #4, June 1951 (Box 5, Folder 125)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.47 #5, July 1951 (Box 5, Folder 126)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.47 #6, August 1951 (Box 5, Folder 127)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.48 #1, September 1951 (Box 5, Folder 128)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.48 #2, October 1951 (Box 5, Folder 129)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.48 #5, January 1952 (Box 6, Folder 130)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.48 #6, February 1952 (Box 6, Folder 131)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.49 #1, March 1952 (Box 6, Folder 132)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.49 #2, April 1952 (Box 6, Folder 133)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.49 #3, May 1952 (Box 6, Folder 134)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.49 #4, June 1952 (Box 6, Folder 135)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.49 #5, July 1952 (Box 6, Folder 136)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.49 #6, August 1952 (Box 6, Folder 137)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.50 #1, September 1952 (Box 6, Folder 138)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.50 #2, October 1952 (Box 6, Folder 139)
    Isaac Asimov, "The Currents of Space", three part serial continued in 50.3, 50.4
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.50 #3, November 1952 (Box 6, Folder 140)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.50 #4, December 1952 (Box 6, Folder 141)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.50 #5, January 1953 (Box 6, Folder 142)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.50 #6, February 1953 (Box 6, Folder 143)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.51 #1, March 1953 (Box 6, Folder 144)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.51 #2, April 1953 (Box 6, Folder 145)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.51 #4, June 1953 (Box 6, Folder 146)
    Philip K. Dick, "Imposter"
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.51 #5, July 1953 (Box 6, Folder 147)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.51 #6, August 1953 (Box 6, Folder 148)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.52 #1, September 1953 (Box 6, Folder 149)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.52 #2, October 1953 (Box 6, Folder 150)
    George Pal, "'Filming War of the Worlds'"
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.52 #3, November 1953 (Box 6, Folder 151)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.52 #4, December 1953 (Box 6, Folder 152)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.52 #5, January 1954 (Box 6, Folder 153)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.52 #6, February 1954 (Box 6, Folder 154)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.53 #1, March 1954 (Box 6, Folder 155)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.53 #2, April 1954 (Box 6, Folder 156)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.53 #3, May 1954 (Box 6, Folder 157)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.53 #4, June 1954 (Box 6, Folder 158)
    Frank Herbert, "Operation Syndrome"
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.53 #5, July 1954 (Box 6, Folder 159)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.54 #1, September 1954 (Box 6, Folder 160)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.54 #2, October 1954 (Box 6, Folder 161)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.54 #3, November 1954 (Box 6, Folder 162)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.54 #4, December 1954 (Box 6, Folder 163)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.54 #5, January 1955 (Box 6, Folder 164)
  - Astounding Science Fiction v.54 #6, February 1955 (Box 6, Folder 165)
- Series III: Ellery Queen's Mystery Magazine
  An incomplete run of issues from May 1943 to March 1961.
  - Ellery Queen's Mystery Magazine v.4 #3, May 1943 (Box 7, Folder 166)
    Jack London, "The Leopard Man's Story"
  - Ellery Queen's Mystery Magazine v.4 #13, November 1943 (Box 7, Folder 167)
    John Dickson Carr, "The Locked Room"
  - Ellery Queen's Mystery Magazine v.5 #14, January 1944 (Box 7, Folder 168)
  - Ellery Queen's Mystery Magazine v.5 #16, May 1944 (Box 7, Folder 169)
  - Ellery Queen's Mystery Magazine v.5 #17, July 1944 (Box 7, Folder 170)
  - Ellery Queen's Mystery Magazine v.5 #18, September 1944 (Box 7, Folder 171)
  - Ellery Queen's Mystery Magazine v.5 #19, November 1944 (Box 7, Folder 172)
  - Ellery Queen's Mystery Magazine v.6 #20, January 1945 (Box 7, Folder 173)
  - Ellery Queen's Mystery Magazine v.6 #21, March 1945 (Box 7, Folder 174)
  - Ellery Queen's Mystery Magazine v.6 #21A, April 1945 (Box 7, Folder 175)
  - Ellery Queen's Mystery Magazine v.6 #22, May 1945 (Box 7, Folder 176)
  - Ellery Queen's Mystery Magazine v.6 #22A, June 1945 (Box 7, Folder 177)
  - Ellery Queen's Mystery Magazine v.6 #23, July 1945 (Box 7, Folder 178)
  - Ellery Queen's Mystery Magazine v.6 #23A, August 1945 (Box 7, Folder 179)
  - Ellery Queen's Mystery Magazine v.7 #26, January 1946 (Box 7, Folder 180)